So before we dive into day three, let me
once again say thank you to the two of
you, to everyone behind the glass and to
you Bird gang as well. Really appreciate
all the messages, the congratulations on
10,000 episodes. Very, very cool. It's
really appreciated. And more
importantly, I think appreciated by
everyone who has had a hand in this
show. It's not just about me.
>> She gets all the credit for yesterday.
By the way, there is, if anyone's
wondering, unless Darren has gotten his
hands on the cake, there is still
leftover cake from last night's show.
>> Okay, good to know.
>> Probably will stay that way.
>> No, you could take it home, Zach.
>> No, we No.
>> No. Okay.
>> No.
>> All right. With that said, we move
forward to the next 10,00.
Four more picks made here on day three.
Four more players added. And as Danny
noted earlier on social media, this is
the first time Monty Austin Ford has not
made a trade in his three years as
general manager.
>> Does my memory also serve me correct?
This is the first draft he did not take
a Buckeye.
>> Correct.
>> What's going on with Ohio State
>> or select a defensive back? Either a
corner or a safety.
>> See, we were having this conversation.
We'll get into it right off the top. Wh
why would they why would that be a
problem?
>> I'm just making a a statement. If you're
looking at what he hasn't done through
the first every single that has been a
glaring need the last three years. It is
not a glaring need right now.
>> Stick with trends. Monty has also had
the fourth straight draft without
drafting a punter.
>> Okay, now we might just X you right out
of this show
>> potentially.
>> Um shifted to cover two very fast.
>> Exactly. Uh for those that might have
missed it, here are the four players
added here on this Saturday. Caleb
Proctor, defensive lineman in the fourth
round. Reggie Virgil, wide receiver,
fifth round, linebacker, Carson Sh in
the sixth round, and an offensive
tackle, Jaden Williams, in the seventh
round. How about we go just one by one
here, and then we can kind of look at
the entire seven player class. But first
things first with the 104th overall
pick, we call this the Ron Wolfley
selection. He was pick 104 and he always
likes to make sure everyone remembers
that he was pick 104. Caleb Proctor,
senior out of southeastern Louisiana,
62291.
And first things first, um, props to Roy
Lopez who made the announcement in
Mexico City and I think did it great
justice. And for anyone that would like
to have their announcement, I think now
you want Roy Lopez to make the draft
announcement if it's not the
commissioner, Roger Goodell. He brought
the energy and and he got to welcome his
new teammate in the position room. A
defensive tackle, three-year starter, 13
games played and started last year for
Caleb Proctor. He finished with 43
tackles, 13 of those for loss in nine
sacks. He was the Southland player of
the year and and what's important to
remember is that the scouting department
is going to look at specific tape. you
you look overall, but you want to see a
player coming out of a school like
Southeastern Louisiana, and you want to
see how they played against FBS teams.
And so that's what the scouting
department was really looking at. And
and I like the pick. I I think this was,
first of all, a need for this team. Uh
they're looking to beef up the trenches.
We saw that with some free agency moves,
looking to be more formidable and stop
the run better than last year. And
there's question marks around Kus
Campbell, which I know we'll talk about
later on after hearing from the GM after
the draft concluded Saturday on what his
future is going to look like. And so
you're at the point where yes, it is
still a position of need, but best
player available, an athletic defender,
and this is someone who can come in and
and if he can get a spot early on in a
rotation, which is definitely doable,
Zack, in this defense under DC Nick
Rollis, it's possible that we'll see
Caleb Proctor out there early on in his
rookie year. And we've seen a handful of
guys, especially at the defensive
tackle, defensive line positions that
have the ability that came from the FCS
level, and have been able to adjust what
what Kobe Turner, I know he had the one
year at Wake Forest, but his time at
Richmond, and I saw one of the tweets, I
believe it came from the folks at the
East West Shrine Bowl. Uh they said like
this could be the next Kobe Turner. And
I asked him about that just like if he's
talked to some of the guys. He talked to
Jayl Hunt who won a Super Bowl in his
first year with Philadelphia and was a
key member of that rotation over there
in Philly. So, he's starting to see what
the formula is. And and to kind of echo
a little bit of Danny's point about the
Southland Conference player of the year,
they still have an offensive player of
the year and a defensive player of the
year. He was neither. He was the
conference player of the year as a
whole. So, uh the Cardinals seem to have
had a seem to have selected a pretty
good one over there.
>> Led the team in sacks with nine, two of
those against LSU. So, if you're looking
for trying to find out, can he handle
the increased competition, one, you look
at the LSU game, two, you look at his
work at the East West Shrine game and
the week's worth of practice, something
that assistant GM Dave Sears made
mention on Saturday. So, you kind of get
a sense or try to get a little bit more
of an evaluation based off who you're
going up against. It's always tough when
you're getting into day three selection.
>> Exactly. And when you have the the
string of practices as well, like Dave
was talking about, that's an important
part of the evaluation. But the one
thing that he did take away from his
conversation with Jayix, was the fact
that at the end of the day, football is
still football. No matter where, no
matter how you got into the building, no
matter what school you went to, once you
are in this building, the game is still
the same. And the the techniques, the
fundamentals, the overall message of get
to the quarterback and bring them down
and get to the backfield. Danny, that's
the overall message. and he's saying,
"Hey, regardless of the fact that I went
to Southeastern Louisiana, we're now in
the same league and you still have to
line up across from me."
>> 35 career starts for Proctor. He's able
to use his long arms to win his reps.
And this this won't make a difference
whether or not, not just him, any player
is successful in the NFL. I do think
it's worth noting the loyalty that
Proctor showed to his teammates and to
that program. He had offers from FBS
schools and he made it clear that he
wanted to stay his senior year and he
wanted to ride that thing out with his
teammates who he called his brothers who
will be standing up at his wedding
someday. And you know in the day and age
of NIL and all these things where you
can understand why players want to go
and make personal decisions that says a
lot about who he is as a teammate
>> and he had very heavy heavy interest is
what he was saying. That's a direct
quote from him. So that that that does
say a lot in a world where loyalty is
not necessarily a thing. Uh to have
somebody like Jeremiah Love said in his
introductory press conference when your
word can be bond I think that says a
lot. Mel Kyper Jr. on the ESPN broadcast
called Proctor quote a complete
defensive tackle. He's a bit undized and
it's something that he acknowledged on
the conference call but uses his arm
length his quickness and as Dave Sears
mentioned low man wins. So, it's going
to be a little bit more about technique,
trying to figure out your footwork, your
hand placement with Proctor because he
doesn't h I mean, he he's 6'2 291, so
it's not like he's small, but when
you're lined up against 6'4, 300 plus,
there's a little bit of a difference.
>> Too soon to look ahead to training camp
battles of round two pick offensive
lineman Chase Vzantis and round four
pick defensive tackle Caleb Proctor. I
know you're It's not too early for you,
Craig. I either
>> absolutely not. Everyone loves
one-on-one O line D line.
>> I just did a little quick research
though, a player that also was recently
in the Southwind Conference, Cam Ward
before he transferred up. So, you have a
lot of good talent that he was playing
against.
>> So, no other move in the fourth round.
So, we had to wait until the fifth round
for the Cardinals next selection. 143rd
overall, the Cardinals go offense. Wide
receiver Reggie Virgil, senior out of
Texas Tech, 631 187. And the we'll get
to the numbers here in a moment, but the
funny antidote with this or the anecdote
with this pick was what Reggie told us
on the conference call because everyone
looks at his combine 40, his proday 40,
a 457, and then a 461. Not great. Reggie
acknowledged that, but then made mention
that Monty Austin Ford said, "Hey, I'm
glad you ran slow, so you moved down
draft boards to allow us to take you in
the fifth round." And then Monty after
the draft said, "Look, you turn on the
tape, maybe you didn't run fast,
straight line, but on the tape, he does
not look slow or play slow."
>> Look, you're going to need different
kinds of receivers to be successful. And
so, you don't need every receiver to be
someone who can take the top off. And I
and I'm not sure that's what this
coaching staff in front office would
expect off the bat from a fifth round
pick even to begin with. So, if you have
other tangibles or intangibles of the
size, the strength, the route running,
right, and and and being able to create
separation and win one-on- ons, take
that. if they don't have the quote
unquote top speed that you might be
looking for and you can find another
player. I see this as someone who will
probably make the team on special teams
and maybe have a role similar to a semi
foko of of kind of being maybe that
fourth string wide receiver and and
maybe being used in some packages.
Remember they brought in Kendrick Bourne
in free agency. They did bring back
Simei Foko under, of course, Michael
Wilson and Marvin Harrison Jr. So,
there's not this intense pressure to
come in and and automatically fight for
that third string role, but this is
going to be an opportunity to kind of
develop a receiver. And that's part of
the draft, Zach, because you see a
player who plays well in college,
they're winning consistently, and you
can see the potential. And so, you you
kind of take that risk, and I'm not
saying this is a bigger risk than
others, but just the draft in general of
this is a good player. Let's see what he
can do.
>> Yeah. Look, when you're able to make it
to a day three selection, which is still
an achievement in and of itself, you
kind of go into it knowing that the way
to crack a 53man roster is through
special teams. When he was at Miami of
Ohio before he te before he transferred
over to Texas Tech, he played tons of
special teams. And he even said, "I was
a dog on special teams." And when he
went to Texas Tech, obviously he's your
number one wide receiver. You're not
going to have him playing a lot of
special teams snaps and a lot and being
a part of a lot of coverages. But it's
the it's the fact that you know he can
go play special teams. And when you look
at some ways that he can crack the
roster from an offensive perspective,
it's his size. He's 6'3. And you look at
some of the other guys in the room.
Kendrick Bourne 6'1, Michael Wilson 6'2,
Marvin Harrison Jr. 6'3. You're starting
to sense that theme. We were talking
about yesterday with the identity,
Danny, of what you want some of these
guys to be. and in the way that he runs.
I know the speed like we talked about
when you're clocking it in and you you
do the the test and sometimes the tests
aren't always going to give the full
answer, but but Craig that that 4.57 is
only for the quick 40-yard dash. You put
your hand into the dirt and you start
running. In his case, he's a tall dude.
He's lengthy and he could open the the
defense up quite a bit. two years ago
when he was at Miami of Ohio, a second
team allac performer, he averaged almost
20 yards a catch, which was seventh best
in the country. So that to me doesn't
say you're a slow receiver. Now maybe
you're not a burner, but you're able to
one gain separation off the line of
scrimmage. You run good routes so the
quarterback can throw you open and you
catch the ball on the run and you're not
going down on first contact. So 20 yards
every time you touch the football on
average. Again, two years ago, that's
impressive no matter what level you're
playing.
>> When you look at the numbers for Virgil,
I mean, last year it wasn't like he had
a bad year. This is not the one where
you're talking about he doesn't have
this incredible speed from the from the
combine. Why do they take him? No, he
led the team in receptions with 57. He
had 705 receiving yards. He averaged
12.4 four per catch and six touchdowns
>> plus two rushing touchdowns. Two rushing
touchdowns. I mean, yeah, it's the
numbers are there. The production is
there. Just get open and catch the ball.
And that's what he was able to do all
throughout his career. I mean, you look
at the first two years when he was at
Miami of Ohio. Slowly got into it, but
then it was that junior year where he
really started to make a name for
himself. And it was with the numbers
that you rattled off. There's a reason
why he was able to get that NIL money
probably and take that jump to Texas
Tech. That doesn't happen by accident.
That wasn't just a one-year thing. And
he proved that. And one of the things I
asked him about was how can you learn
from that step up from Miami of Ohio
playing in the MAC to going to the Big
12 to the NFL. And he just said it comes
down to the hard work and the
preparation and studying and working
with some of the receiving coaches and
the passing game coordinators at Tech
that opens up the doors for some of
these opportunities. also performed very
well at the Senior Bowl. He was among
the 10 players that Daniel Jeremiah
singled out as far as the week of
practice with Daniel riding excellent
size, very smooth with the speed to take
the top off the defense. I like his
production, too. 15 touchdowns over the
past two seasons. So, you look at the
wide receiver room now and you've got 12
wide receivers there. You keep what?
five, at least five, probably six. It's
a brand new coaching staff, but the
competition in that wide receiver room
certainly
>> you increase your value if you're Virgil
if you can play on special teams as well
to give yourself a uniform on game day.
>> Well, let's also I want to kind of go to
the the call though and the way that he
spoke to us in the media. I know it was
only just a few minutes, but he kind of
gives me Kendrick Bourne vibes. the
personality,
>> the personality, the willingness to take
that step up as you continue to to grow
throughout your career going from a
college player to a professional player
and who's the coach that gets credited
for Kendrick Bourne's success, Mike
Lefor. So, you start to see what that
wide receiver coach mindset that Leffor
has, how that can translate and help a
guy like Reggie. Now, we're not saying
right now he's going to be wide receiver
one. That's unrealistic. But it's just
the fact that you want to see these guys
whatever sort of advantage that they
could possibly have. I think having a
vet like Kendrick Bourne in the room. I
remember when he was talking to you,
Danny, he talked about the desire to be
that veteran and help some of these guys
out. If you're Reggie, you got to be a
sponge.
>> Well, well, not even just Virgil. I
mean, when you're talking about 12
receivers, I'm thinking, holy smokes.
And you got to go look, right? And
there's players that the Cardinals added
late last year, but this is going to be
competition for players like Xavier
Weaver, a Palmer, former late draft pick
for the Cardinals, right? Jaylen Brooks,
who they brought in late last year. So,
there's going to be some good
competition to round out that wide
receivers room. Absolutely.
>> You you bring up Kendrick Bourne, Zach,
I think it's a good mention. Bourne
wasn't even drafted. Yeah.
>> And now here you have Reggie Virgil who
got his name called on day three in the
fifth round. Moving to the Cardinals
sixth round selection. Number 183
overall, the Cardinals go defense.
Carson Shy, senior out of Iowa. Inside
linebacker, 61, 231.
first year or one year starter last
season, 13 starts, led the team in
tackles with 83, had 12 tackles for
loss, four sacks, one pass defense, one
forced fumble, honorable mention, all
Big 10. And here's someone that likes
the versatility at the linebacker
position. And again, you're on day
three, so you're talking about special
teams, but comes in to a room with M.
Wilson, with Cody Simon, with Jack
Gibbons, who you brought in over in free
agency. So, some experience within the
room and now you get a little bit
younger.
>> Yeah, Jay Higgins was the linebacker
that he was sitting behind at Iowa and
then this was the year where he was
really able to start taking it over and
he was talking about his ability to play
Mike linebacker and will linebacker and
also his speed. He is a fast dude. I'm
pretty sure he clocked in in the top 10
of fastest linebackers at the scouting
combine. And to knock on Reggie, we just
talked about the the differences in
that, but when you watch the tape, it's
his speed and the way that he's able to
kind of have these delay blitzes a
little bit and then just go after the
quarterback. When you Google his name or
you look up on on X, you see a lot of
highlight hit sticks plays because he
just has that speed, Danny, that when he
sees ball, I'm going to get ball.
>> It wasn't by much. 01, but that was the
difference of Sh was faster than Virgil
40 yard dash the combine. When we
mention special teams, it's not just he
has a skill. I mean, he's been a dog on
special teams in college. He's got
almost 600 career snaps. I mean, he led
his team in tackles and tackles for loss
with Iowa last year. It was 83 tackles,
12 of those for loss, four sacks. So,
this this to me is a good pick because,
okay, you know, you're gonna get
something out of him on special teams
from the jump. And then this is a young
player who has shown good ability and
and being out on the defensive side of
the ball as well. And what he's shown
and being a linebacker and that's a room
that's a position where depth is always
a very good thing to have.
>> And then we can get into what that room
might look like because edge rusher was
not addressed in the draft. Does things
change within that inside linebacker
room because you can utilize maybe M.
Wilson a little bit more after the
quarterback and change things up a
little bit depending on who's in that
front seven.
>> That's been a discussion we've had and
I'm sure we will have. Does that answer
change by drafting Carson Shire? No.
>> It just gives you another body in that
room more depth to maybe play with some
different pieces
>> maybe. I I'm I'm not I'm not sold that
those those two things are necessarily
going to be correlated just from where
Sh is going to be projected to be on the
depth chart, but it's a possibility.
>> Yeah. Right now, when I look at
potentially moving players around, and
obviously it's still early, you need to
see how far along Cody Simon is in his
development going from year one to year
number two, you have to see how Jack
Gibbons does in a Nick Rollis system
before you could even think about ways
that you and you should still think
about ways to get M. Wilson senior off
the edge. But in terms of keeping him in
that Mike linebacker spot, the green
dot, I I don't think that there could be
any discussion. I am a little bit
surprised. There there are players that
were on the board that on the edge
position around this time that I was
surprised was not taken. Kaden Curry, an
Ohio State Buckeye, I thought was was a
layup for the Cardinals to take. He led
the Buckeyes in sacks and his ability to
work with Arvel Ree. I thought that that
was something that was interesting. But
obviously the scouts see it in a
different way because he still fell all
the way to the seventh round. So in this
linebacker position, at least off the
edge, the Cardinals feel good enough
about where they're at. They say a lot
of guys have played a lot of ball so
far. Obviously Josh Sweat is still going
to be the headline name in that room.
But M. Wilson senior, you need to still
have him kind of patrolling the defense.
He already tweeted as he typically does
uh calling Carson his rook. So he's got
another one added to the list. He's been
the most active veteran on Twitter. Very
excited for this new wave of Cardinals.
>> Dane Bugler, who authors the beast, this
is what he wrote about Shy, needs to
prove himself trustworthy in his eye
discipline and coverage recognition, but
his speed and toughness are enough to
make an impact on special teams. So, if
it doesn't work where you're playing
defense, again, it's all about do you
have a uniform? Are you active on game
day? someone loses a shoe, then all of a
sudden you're the next man up.
>> And it's at the end of the day, see
ball, get ball. That's what he did. And
Dave Sears said the same thing on
special teams. He said that Carson is
the type of player that he will run
through your face and not put the brakes
on while doing it.
>> The final pick for the Arizona Cardinals
in the 2026 NFL draft with the first
pick in the seventh round, 217 overall.
The Cardinals go back to the offensive
side of the ball. Offensive tackle Jaden
Williams, senior out of Miss, 6'4, 310
pounds, 45 games, 34 career starts, can
play both the left tackle and right
tackle positions. So, you got some
versatility, a little bit more
experience on the left tackle side, but
not much. And here's someone that's
going to come in and look, we talk about
special teams, yes, but come in and
maybe be a little bit of a I won't say
project, but someone that can come in
and really take to the NFL teaching,
whether that's Justin Fry or Chris Cook,
who they already have a relationship
with, having spent some time together at
the East West Shrine game. So you can
continue to build on that and get
perhaps Williams to the point where hey
can be someone that you trust on the
tackle side.
>> Not not using project in a bad way. This
is just more of a developmental pick and
and that's because when you're looking
at this offensive line and even top O
linemen in the draft typically need a
year to really gain weight and gain
muscle and make sure that their hand and
their footwork and and the placement and
the speed is going to consistently win
against 300 lb defensive linemen and
when you're having to create gaps that
are a lot smaller than what you're used
to in college. But this is a good pick.
I I always am in favor of beefing up the
trenches and adding depth there. This
coaching staff and and front office
really uh likes what they see in at
least the foundation for Jaden Williams
coming out of Miss 6'4 307. So that's a
big player already have versatility off
the bat which which is huge especially
for this coaching staff and for Monty
Austin. Something that we have seen in
almost every offensive lineman he has
taken in the draft is their ability to
play on both sides of the line. Zach,
>> and the call when we spoke to him, he
was one of the first people that I feel
like was actually very real and very
just the emotions you could hear on the
call and he said like it's been
stressful. He's a guy that's gone
through injuries, has been sidelined in
two different years during his time at
Old Miss. he transitions for the
betterment of the team and moves from a
left tackle where he's played his entire
career all the way to a right tackle and
did pretty well at that. And then you're
going through this process here and his
counterpart on the left side of the
lines, Diego Pounds, is the guy that's
kind of getting a little bit more
notoriety, but it's what Jaden was able
to do on the right side, keep Trinidad
Chamblas upright, lead them all the way
to a festival semi-final appearance. I I
think it uh I I think it was pretty
impressive to see what he had been able
to do. At the end of the day though,
it's keeping the quarterback upright.
That's the most important job. I did
appreciate though how he said like he's
excited to get back to State Farm
Stadium and actually come home with a
win this time.
>> Yeah, he's been there once and now hopes
to be there several times in his Arizona
Cardinals career. Couple of notes about
his athleticism as far as footwork.
Maybe it translates, maybe it doesn't,
but played forward, played center for
his high school basketball team, led
them to a state championship his junior
year, and again, this is going way back,
but began his football career as a wide
receiver. Now he's a 300B offensive
tackle.
>> Good hands.
>> There you go. And then how he naturally
moved over to the left side of the line
as he went from being a wide receiver to
a tight end to then them saying, "Hey
man, you're big and you weigh a lot. Go
play on the left side of the line."
block the guy coming after the
quarterback. And it was a question after
we got the discussion about Jaden
Williams. The question about all right,
if you're to play a game this week, who
is your starting right tackle? I believe
it was your question, Danny, to GM Any
Austin Ford. And the answer was, well,
we're not naming anyone a starter.
Although there were some nice things to
say about Elijah Wilkinson, who the
Cardinals signed in free agency. Yeah, I
started every game for the Falcons last
year. Wilkinson has experience on both
sides of the line. And when you're
looking at the depth chart, where things
stand right now, which could very well
change from the end of April to the
beginning of September, that seems to
make the most sense. And without
confirming it, that is what Awesome Fort
was essentially implying between the
lines. You know, when when you're
looking at their draft selections, the
rest of their free agency acquisitions,
Isaac Samalu is going to be the left
guard. Isaiah Adams is going to be right
now the starting right guard. I think
there will be some competition with
upcoming rookie Chase Bantis there at
the guard position, but that makes sense
to hear Wilkinson. Again, not
officially, but his name is definitely
in the mix, I believe, were the words
that Austin used for that starting right
tackle job.
>> Yeah, we talk about Jaden Williams and
what his potential could be. You look at
a guy, an undrafted rookie last year in
Josh Frier and how they kept him still
in the building and because of injuries,
he had to work his way up to being a
starter because in the NFL, yes, you
could work your way up, but a good
amount of the time you're just going to
get thrown into the fire and you're
going to have to just learn on the fly.
And that's essentially what Josh Frier
did. So, you look towards the future of
the position when you start to think
about week one. It looks like right now
you brought in a 16g game starter in
Elijah Wilkinson over a guy going down
into a second year. You start to read
between the lines a little bit. It looks
like it's going to be Elijah Wilkinson.
But just like we talked about with Cody
Simon, what does that secondyear jump
look like for a guy like Josh Frier now
that he's actually been in it? He has
gone against some really good defensive
linemen. You think about the Los Angeles
Rams who we played in that last game of
the year. you're going up against two
outside linebackers that both made the
Pro Bowl. So, he learned a lot by
getting thrown into the fire. What does
that year two look like? Can he put up a
competition with Elijah Wilkinson? It'll
be a fascinating training camp
discussion. Other tackles on the roster,
Christian Jones, Damontre Jacobs, you
signed Ole Udo in free agency. So again,
it's
and then there was the question about
all right, what's next when it comes to
roster construction? And Monty mentioned
that they'll keep an eye on what happens
over the next week to two weeks because
now that you've got the draft, you begin
to add undrafted rookie free agents. Do
other players become available? Because
if you're going to bring someone in and
you hit that 90 man limit, do you have
to let someone go? There's always that
other wave of players that potentially
could be available for the Cardinals or
any other NFL team.
>> Absolutely. But not to come compete with
Elijah Wilkinson as the starting right.
>> I wouldn't think you're going to because
>> you're just saying in general.
>> In general. Yeah. I mean, as far as
adding to certain rooms, this Cardinals
team is going to sign about a half a
dozen undrafted rookies. The roster
right now, I believe, is at 84. You can
get to 90. Certainly, you can sign more
than you want, but then you've got to
release someone to maintain that 90man
limit here in the offseason.
>> We're going to start hitting es and
flows of transactions happening around
the league. You know, the first one
happens at the start of the new league
year in the middle of March with free
agency. Then it dies down and you get to
the draft. And then as players get to
those or teams rather get to the full 90
men on the roster, you'll start to have
these offseason programs of mini camp
OTAAS and and things will happen whether
that's injury, whether that is realizing
a player is not a good fit or for
whatever reason they decide to move on.
So you'll have some waves throughout the
summer and then again in training camp
when that first big cut happens.
>> Yeah, we see it all the time. Even
during training camp, there's going to
be a lot of people. It's a rotating
door. A lot of players are going to be
having new jersey numbers and there's
going to be a lot of changes with a lot
of players are going to have the same
jersey number even as matching with
somebody else because you're trying to
trim this roster down from 90 to 53. But
once they get out onto the football
field and it kind of goes to what Monty
Austin's talking about. We could play
the paper game all day long of looking
at the roster and saying this team can
be x y and z. They could win this amount
of games. At the end of the day, you
don't know until they actually get out
onto the practice field at State Farm
Stadium come training camp.
>> Looking at all four players who were
selected on Saturday, all four stood out
in the postseason all-star games,
whether it was the East West Shrine game
or the Senior Bowl. And again, that I
think is where those day three picks and
maybe even later day two picks can
really separate themselves or show up
and hey, don't forget about me and
really grab the attention of coaches who
are coaching in those games. Several
Arizona Cardinals coaches are a part of
that and then the scouts who are in
attendance and then the extra film
because you're not going up against your
own teammates. It's a different set of
circumstances as far as another player
from maybe the same conference or a
different conference, but it's part of
that evaluation process that we've seen
over the years that this Cardinals front
office really values what they see from
players in these postseason all-star
games.
>> It's a great opportunity when position
coaches get those opportunities to show
what they're capable of doing as a coach
in some of those all-star games. And
it's invaluable information for the
organizations that they are a part of.
Look, you you can watch the tape as a
scout and you can get a good idea. You
can go and you can sit in the bleachers
and you can watch consistent days of
practice and you can get a good idea.
Having a coach in there though and
seeing how they are watching film as a
player themselves, how are they in
meeting rooms, how coachable are they,
what is their temperament, how
respectful are they to their teammates,
to what the coaching staff is asking of
them. Those are the intangible things
that really make a difference from those
all-star games. And you look at some of
the guys that are currently on the
roster that earned their way through
obviously what they did in college but
really stood out in those all-star game
processes. You start to see Michael
Wilson, Darius Robinson, what both of
them were able to do at the Senior Bowl.
You look at the Shrine Bowl, Tip Ryman,
Rabbit Taylor Demerson, Starling Thomas
didn't even get a combine invite. The
only time the Cardinals saw him was
during the East West Shrine Bowl. So,
when you start to see that a little bit,
it helps your your process as you're
starting to put together your big board
and you're starting to say, "Man, these
are the type of guys that we really want
to have and we're going to circle." And
you have that familiarity. It does make
a massive difference. And also, we talk
about playing under the big lights.
These guys know that these these are
interviews at the end of the day. Sure,
when you're when you're playing a game,
you're trying to win and that's going to
be what you're ultimately going to put
on tape. These are the ultimate
interviews for a lot of these players.
Seven players added in this draft class.
Five of them on offense. A year ago,
seven players, but just one on offense.
And you look at this class overall,
Danny, certainly the headline's going to
be Jeremiah Love. My guess is the sub
headline's going to be Carson Beck just
because of the position that he plays.
But overall, you look at going best
player available versus or in addition
to where do you have needs or perhaps
fill some holes that you might have or
add depth because again your needs in
April aren't necessarily your needs in
September or October.
>> Sometimes there's a player that's simply
too good to pass up on. That's what
Jeremiah Love at three really feels
like. Not a glaring right now, very well
could be. And we saw that from the
Cardinals run game last year. James
Connor went down third game of the
season. Fourth game, you lose Trey
Benson. By the end of the season,
Cardinals are on their sixth and seventh
string running backs. That was tough.
Now, run game struggled for other
reasons like, you know, bringing in a
different quarterback and rocking with
Jacobe Brassette and and a struggling
and hurt offensive line. All those
things to consider. Although, this was a
run game that struggled even before
Connor and Benson got hurt last year.
So, that was an area they were going to
want to look to improve already, which
we also saw through other draft picks
and free agency and really bolstering
the offensive line. What what happens
though in those situations, right,
when you're looking at maybe justifying,
so to speak, this pick is what happens
if you have a player like Connor get
hurt. Okay. Well, then you have Tyler
Algier who you brought in. He's been a
feature back the last three years behind
Bejian Robinson in Atlanta. He was great
as the as the featured back. His rookie
year with the Falcons, he had a thousand
yards. He hasn't done that a few years.
Is that something he can still do?
There's there's understanding of why
bringing in not just a running back, but
Jeremiah Love specifically at three
really does make sense. This is an
offense that wants to turn the tide.
They want to be more formidable. They do
not want to be one-dimensional, which
they were with the pass game last year.
And he is tough as nails. He's going to
be a tone center. reminds me a lot of
James Connor and talking about how much
he loves to get hit and to hit others.
>> Yeah. When you when you're starting to
see on social media uh accounts are
putting together the the depth chart and
they're saying who's stopping this
offense, that's a pretty good sign. And
what you're doing here is you're
bringing a player that's already being
labeled as a generational prospect in
Jeremiah Love and you're starting to
compare him to some of the greats in the
game. Obviously, there's a lot of
pressure that comes with that. And when
I was with him in Pittsburgh, he was
saying, "I don't feel that pressure
because I'm only going to be focused on
me." I could tell you, we've heard that
same thing from James Connor so many
different times. And you believe it when
James is saying it, which is why I have
no reason to not believe Jeremiah Love
now that he's in this position. At the
end of the day, though, it's all going
to come down to the quarterback
conversation. That's going to be
something that will be addressed in
these coming weeks. And I I just I look
at it. If Carson Beck could be
something, if if Jacobe Brassette has
the ability to start stringing together
some wins, if he's the one that
ultimately does get the start and you
have these weapons, man, Michael Ford
could do a lot of dangerous things. It
would be a certainly a nice change from
a year ago when it was always a struggle
each and every Sunday offensively
because the offense was one-dimensional.
Can you get back to more of a dual
threat with the Arizona Cardinals on
that side of the ball? Before we uh
close up shop here over these past three
days of the draft, there is a non-draft
note that we need to pass along and that
is something that we've kind of been
wanting an answer. We still don't have
an answer, but Kus Campbell, what is his
future? Is there a future with the
Arizona Cardinals?
>> I tried to ask. Did not get a concrete
answer. You know what's interesting is
this is something I was waiting to ask
until the last day of the draft, that
final press conference. And then it was
either I couldn't tell you the days. It
was either late Friday or Saturday
morning and Campbell posted on his
Instagram story. He likes to repost
inspirational videos and he reposted
one, but he added his own caption about
how this was inspiring his training. And
I'm thinking, okay, are we being broad?
Are we being specific? Is this training
just in case because you haven't made up
your mind. Either way, I did try to ask
the GM and Austin for it had a smile of
saying they have talked to Campbell. It
is in his words quote wait and see.
Which he did acknowledge Campbell who
just wrapped up season 18 has earned the
right to do. And when you see how
productive and how tough Campbell was in
18, there's there's no question about
whether or not he could continue that in
season 19. And it's a matter of does he
want to do that physically, mentally,
all he would have to put his body
through. He is a free agent. So Austin
Ford didn't necessarily answer the part
of my question where I asked if the
discussion of whether or not Arizona had
come up on if Campbell wants to play in
season 19, if it would want to be here.
We're going to have to continue to wait
for an answer.
>> It's the Brian Windhorse mean. What does
that mean?
>> What does that mean?
>> I have notifications turned on for Kus.
So anytime I get that notification, it's
okay. Hey, is this an announcement? I'm
coming back. I'm retiring. So, that's
kind of like not on edge, but anytime it
pops up on the phone, you wonder to your
point, all of a sudden, well, is this
just motivation, inspiration? All of a
sudden, oh wait, am I supposed to read
into what this is? And there's an
announcement coming one way or the
other. So, again, we wait and see.
>> Do you get inspired by his repost?
>> Absolutely.
>> Okay. I'm just making sure. I want to
make sure his repost are effective.
>> Is very, very good on social media.
>> He is
>> much better than I am
>> consistent. But look, at the end of the
day, when it comes to Kus, you he's a
he's a legend in this in this league and
he's a legend for this franchise. So,
you want to see him back, but I give
Monty a lot of credit for still saying,
"Hey, I'm giving you the respect. You've
earned it. Uh just let us know." And I
think that that's what these uh coming
weeks are going to be like. We know last
year it was on April Fool's Day on April
1st when he announced that he was going
to be coming back to the Cardinals. for
obviously a few weeks after that, but
I'm sure he's also trying to see what
this Cardinals roster is going to look
like before he makes his decision. It's
his decision and when he makes that
decision, we'll just wait and see. Um,
you speak of, uh, earning stuff. Uh, the
two of you have earned a well-deserved
Sunday off, though we all have to be
back here on Monday because, as they
say, the work never ends.
>> Never ends.
>> But I appreciate the work that everyone
has put in over these three days. They
are productive days. Yes, they are long
days, but this is
these are important three days for the
future, the the immediate and the
long-term future for organizations. And
look, when it comes down to what's
actually being put out there, there are
people, I know draft season's really
when the content Super Bowl really seems
to be for a lot of fans. There are
people that are pressing record. There
are people that are editing. There are
people that are posting. There's a lot
of people that are behind the scenes
that don't necessarily get that credit
and recognition. So, to all those
people, this is their uh their shout out
and kudos because there's too many to
mention.
>> I don't have another cake, though. So,
>> we'll see what
>> they can they can pick up what's left
over.
>> Zack and brings uh brings in on Monday
morning.
>> I'll be ready for the podcast.
>> All the information on all seven players
selected over these three days in the
2026 NFL drafts, go to acardinals.com.
Next stop, well, we've got OTAAS and
mini camp. We'll actually get to see
these players on the field, if you will,
as opposed to just looking at them
through the screen and reading about
them on paper. So, until then, enjoy
what has been a very eventful and
productive three days of the 2026 NFL
draft.